# Ricardo Edwin Flores Maynasa Software Developer

☎ Phone: (+591) 79113527☒ Email: ricky.reflores@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

I'm a software developer with 10+ years of experience in developing and maintaining enterprise-level applications, using current technologies y programming languages such as Java and C#.Net, and participating in every stage of the life cycle of software development, including design, coding, debugging, testing, and maintenance.



I'm passionate about developing and maintaining systems, trying to collaborate with my teammates, and delivering solutions to assist customers to achieve their goals.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming Languages:**

- C# (.Net Framework, .Net Core)
- Java (Spring, Quarkus)
- SQL
- Javascript
- PHP
- Python
- TypeScript

#### **Databases:**

- Microsoft SQL Server
- Cosmos DB
- MySQL

- PostgreSQL
- Oracle
- Redis

### **Technologies and Programs:**

- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- IntelliJ IDEA
- API REST
- Docker/Docker-Compose
- Git/GitHub
- Azure
- Kubernetes
- CI/CD

- GitHub Actions
- Postman

### Systems:

- Linux
- Windows

#### Soft skills:

- Adaptable and Flexible
- Problem-solving
- Teamwork and communication
- Analytical thinking
- Responsibility

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer Mojix Inc. / Towbook

Apr 2020 – Present Remote

- Develop, update, and maintain advanced towing software in .Net Framework, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server, Cosmos DB, and Service Bus to integrate the different background services.
- Migrate and upgrade library, services, and ASP.Net projects in .Net Framework to projects in .Net Standard and .Net 7, to deploy the services on Azure Kubernetes (AKS) using GitHub Actions.

# Freelance Backend Developer Hakan Solutions

Apr 2020 - Feb 2023 Remote

- Build backend services for small fintech projects such as confirming, insurance, and SAC system for the sale of vehicles using the Java language (Quarkus) and PostgreSQL database, integrating with Keycloak as an identity and access manager.
- Build a Notification service to send SMS and email messages in Java (Quarkus) with Twilio and Amazon Simple Email Service (SES).
- Coordinated with front-end and mobile developers to integrate the backend services.
- Build a backend service in Java to consume Libranda API and integrate it with a Woocommerce of Ebooks, build some PHP scripts to interact with backend service to sync the publications, simulate a sell, sell, and download a publication (book).

# Software Engineer CODE ROAD S.R.L. (Mojix Inc.)

Sep 2017 – Apr 2020 La Paz - Bolivia

- Develop and maintain the backend Rest API of the IOT platform in Java and Spring Framework, using Mongo DB, MySQL database, and Apache Kafka.
- Code scripts for MongoDB.
- Code Python scripts to migrate data between different versions of platforms and systems.



• Coordinated with QA and DevOps teams to implement the built solutions.

# Consultant / Senior Developer Ideati - Get Better Consortium

Apr 2016 - Aug 2017 Managua - Nicaragua

- Design and develop a Tax Audit System for "Direccion General de Ingresos" (DGI) of Nicaragua with DDD design architecture, Repository, and Unit of Work patterns, in .Net Framework, Entity Framework, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server, Telerik UI library and Bootstrap frontend toolkit.
- Designed and built a Reporting solution with Reporting Services.

### Consultant / Senior Developer Servicio de Impuestos Nacionales

Jul 2009 - Apr 2016 La Paz - Bolivia

- Design and develop "Galileo" "Modelo de Administración del Sistema Impositivo" (MASI) project, a model that aims to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the Tax Administration that is based on the Business Process Management (BPM) methodology with technologies .Net Framework (C#), Oracle database, and WCF.
- Design and develop the BPM process engine using the XPDL standardized language.
- Modeling the BPM process to register taxpayers.
- Modeling the BPM process of the payment facility.
- Make and layout dynamic views with HTML, CSS, and XSLT into BPM modeling.
- Training on architecture and tools developed for this system.
- Coordinate junior developers' tasks and activities.

### Technical Analyst III Banco de Credito (BCP)

May 2008 - Jul 2009 La Paz - Bolivia

- Maintain and develop features for Internet Banking projects that include account management and banking
  operations, applying CMMI methodology and the Service-oriented Architecture in .Net Framework (C#), Windows
  Communication Foundation (WCF), and SQL Server.
- Design and develop Stored Procedures in the database.
- Make and layout views with HTML and CSS.

### Consultant Software Developer Yacimientos Petroliferos Fiscales Bolivianos (YPFB)

Nov 2007 - May 2008 La Paz - Bolivia

- Develop Accounting, Human Resources, and Billing systems projects, that were implemented in different areas of the company business solutions in .Net Framework (C#), LLGenPro, and Infragistic library.
- Design and develop solutions (projects) with Cake PHP and ExtJS framework.

# IT Product Specialist Answer Consulting Group S.R.L.

Jan 2007 - Nov 2007 La Paz - Bolivia

- Developed an accounting system and a tourist operations system for Crillon Tours company in .Net Framework and SQL Server.
- Developed a documentary system (USAID project) for the "Vice-Presidencia de la Republica de Bolivia" in .Net Framework and SQL Server.
- Training on applications developed.

### **EDUCATION**

System Engineering Degree 2001 - 2006
Universidad Católica Boliviana "San Pablo"

# Certified ScrumMaster (SCM)

2012

Scrum Alliance

## Security Management and Systems Audit Diploma

2012

Universidad de Los Andes

# **LANGUAGES**

SPANISH Native proficiency ENGLISH Medium